(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
新衣装お披露目＆超告知あり！？
Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026 Fashion Beat
New Outfit Reveal & Major Announcements!?
ファッションビート！
Fashion Beat!
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
大空スバル　常闇トワ
Oozora Subaru & Tokoyami Towa
白上フブキ　大神ミオ
Shirakami Fubuki & Ookami Mio
百鬼あやめ　戌神ころね　宝鐘マリン
Nakiri Ayame, Inugami Korone & Houshou Marine
ファッションビート (5)
Fashion Beat (5)
ファッションビート (4)
Fashion Beat (4)
ファッションビート (3)
Fashion Beat (3)
ファッションビート (2)
Fashion Beat (2)
ファッションビート (1)
Fashion Beat (1)
ファッションビート
Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026 Fashion Beat
Fashion Beat
DAI DAI DAI ファンタジスタ
[Song: Great Great Great Fantasista]
Nya! Hello!!
The beautiful days!!
刮目しちゃってくれ!
Keep your eyes on me!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call me "Elite"!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
さぁ、待ったはなしだ!
Well, no more waiting!
始めちゃえ!
Let's get started!
今日も 気ぃ引き締めて
Keep it together today too,
えいや! で挑戦だ
and take on the challenge!
躊躇は厳禁
Hesitation is forbidden,
足踏みしてないで
don't just stand there.
一緒に「せぇの!」でもっと
Let's go "One, two!" and...
前に行こう ね?
...move further ahead, okay?
さぁ、なんとかなっちゃえ!
Well, it'll work out somehow!
飛び込んで
Just dive in!
なんたって ジッとしたっても
Because even if you stay still,
人生は冒険だ
life is an adventure!
こんがらがったら
If you get all tangled up,
またわかんないぞ
you won't understand it again.
道のりは困難だ! なんなんだ! 上等だ!
The path is difficult! So what! Bring it on!
ダンダンダン!
Dan Dan Dan!
(あっぱぁ)
(Appa)
メソメソしちゃって
Sniffling and crying,
気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
putting your feelings on hold.
あれ? 一体全体どうしたん?
Huh? What on earth happened?
絶体絶命?
In a desperate situation?
君たちには
To all of you,
涙は似合わないね!
tears really don't suit you!
大大大大冒険に
Into a great, great, great adventure,
飛び出そうぜ! 良いじゃんねぇ!
let's jump out! It's great, isn't it!
大大大大失敗も
Stack up great, great, great failures,
重ねて成長して
and grow through them.
Happyな feel soで
With a happy "feel so",
君と笑い話にしよう
let's make it a funny story together.
(うぇい)
(Wei!)
大大大大問題も
Even great, great, great problems,
吹き飛ばせ! いつか
blow them away! Someday,
大大大大団円の
to a great, great, great finale,
素敵な結末へ
to a wonderful conclusion!
Please me!! さぁ、付いてきて?
Please me!! Now, will you follow me?
進め! 前代未聞の
Forward! To an unprecedented...
New world!
(Let's go!!)
あながち間違ってる ま～た墓穴も掘ってる
I'm not necessarily wrong, digging my own grave again.
勉強! 勉強! (はいはいはい、知ってます。待って、なんか違ってる!)
Study! Study! (Yes, yes, I know. Wait, something's wrong!)
ぶっちゃけ 有識者の皆様に感謝してます!
Honestly, I'm grateful to all the experts!
Nice comment's 待ってんぜ (あ～ね)
Waiting for your nice comments! (Ah, right)
ウジウジしちゃって 心にロックしちゃって
Fretting around, locking up your heart.
ほら、だんだん だんだん ダウンしちゃ
Look, you're gradually, gradually going down.
絶体絶命!?
In a desperate situation!?
君たちには
To all of you,
笑顔が足りてないね!
you're lacking enough smiles!
大大大大大好きじゃ 済まさない! 良いじゃんねぇ!
Just a great, great, great love isn't enough! It's great, right!
大大大大満足の その上の 感動を!
Great, great, great satisfaction, and moving beyond that!
もっと欲しがっちゃって? 豪快に
Want more of it? Splurge on it!
贅沢に行こう
Let's go in luxury!
(うぇい)
(Wei!)
全然前進しないなって 凹んじゃったって ならば
If you're depressed because you're not moving forward at all, then...
全身全霊 エンジン全開 本気(マジ)の全力で
...with your whole heart and soul, engine at full blast, with your serious best!
Nya! Hello!! さぁbeautifulに!
Nya! Hello!! Now, beautifully!
意気込んで 進め! Freedom way!
With enthusiasm, forward! Freedom way!
(wow wow) 乗り遅れんなよ 皆!
(wow wow) Don't be left behind, everyone!
(wow wow) 声を聞かせてくれ! Yeah!
(wow wow) Let me hear your voices! Yeah!
(wow wow) 歌おう 声高らかに
(wow wow) Let's sing with our voices held high!
(wow wow) ベイベー ベイベー なんていうか…
(wow wow) Baby, baby, how should I put it...
あぁ、なんだかちょっと 言い表せない
Ah, I can't quite describe it.
一人ぼっちで 見てた光景を
The scenery I used to look at all alone,
今はきっと あなたと冒険してる!
I'm surely adventuring with you now!
大大大大大大大大大大大大大大大大大大大好きじゃ 収まらない!
Even a great x20 love isn't enough to contain it!
だだから 最大最高レベルに ガチの全力で!
So, at the maximum, highest level, with my serious best!
Nya! Hello!! 届けちゃうぜ! ずっと大冒険しよう
Nya! Hello!! I'll deliver it! Let's have a great adventure forever!
Yeah!!
大大大大問題も 吹き飛ばせ! いつか
Even great, great, great problems, blow them away! Someday,
大大大大団円の 素敵な結末へ
to a great, great, great finale, to a wonderful conclusion!
Please me!! さぁ、付いてきて?
Please me!! Now, will you follow me?
進め! 前代未聞の New world!
Forward! To an unprecedented new world!
刮目しちゃってくれ!
Keep your eyes on me!
Please call 『Elite』!!
Please call me "Elite"!!
(Funky dancin baby! ah)
(Ah!)
とくべつ、して
[Song: Special, for me]
「とくベチュ、して?」
"Special chu, for me?"
Oh baby「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough.
一番 大事がいい
I want to be the most important.
君が作るオリジナルの
Your own original...
特別、チューして。
...special kiss, please.
まぶしくて、目がさめて
Dazzling light, and I wake up
Oh yeah!
いとしくおもってよ
Please think of me fondly
Oh yeah!
眠り姫のように
Like a sleeping princess
やさしくくちづけて
Gently give me a kiss
ゴミめいたこの世界
This world that feels like trash
Oh yeah!
ピュアがかる君がいる
Has you, tinged with purity
Oh yeah!
すべてにふれずに
Without touching anything
ふたりだけでいよう
Let's just be the two of us
私のこと
Me,
独占して
monopolize me,
君だけのモノになってもいい
it's okay if I become yours alone
なんでもある日の
In a day where everything exists,
「なんでもない」
the "nothing special,"
気付いてね
please notice it
Oh baby I love you! じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
君の『特別』にして
Make me your "special one"
ねぇ もっと
Hey, more,
Give me a kiss
もう私は
I am already
君でいっぱいよ
full of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie my pinky tight
そうよ
That's right,
一生一緒がいいもん
I want to be together forever
とくべちゅが欲しい
I want your special kiss
2人きり週末は
On weekends with just the two of us
Oh yeah!
奏でてよ ハーモニー
Play the harmony
Oh yeah!
流れ星見たら
If you see a shooting star
私を想ってほしい
I want you to think of me
あまあまな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet,
Oh yeah!
広い街 吸い込まれ
absorbed by the wide city,
Oh yeah!
戦う姿に
in your fighting form,
大きいなはなまるだね
you get a big gold star
好きなところ、
The things I like,
優しいとこ。
your kindness.
嫌いなとこも、
Even the things I hate,
優しいとこ。
your kindness.
誰にもあげない
I won't give you to anyone
私だけ
Just for me,
独り占め！
monopolize you!
う～だって今までの人と
U~, because with people up until now,
同じはいらないんです
I don't want the same thing
ねぇ もっと Give me more love
Hey, more, give me more love
私のため
For my sake,
生きてほしいんです
I want you to live
だからウサギと私は
That's why bunnies and I
寂しくさせないで
please don't let us be lonely
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ
Something like that isn't restraint
苦しいのが好き
I like the painfulness
ショートケーキ
Shortcake,
イチゴみたいに
like a strawberry,
座ってもいい？
is it okay to sit?
赤く甘い恋だもん
It's a red, sweet love after all
誰かにあげた
The "I love you"
「大好き」も
you gave to someone else,
返してもらって 全部私に
get it back and give it all to me
ちょーだい もっと！
Give it to me, more!
君は神様が作る
You are a person like a miracle
奇跡のようなヒト
created by God
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your sulky face, and that sleeping face too,
守ってあげるね
I'll protect them for you
Oh baby I love you! じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" isn't enough
君の『特別』にして
Make me your "special one"
ねぇ もっと
Hey, more,
Give me a kiss
もう私は
I am already
君でいっぱいよ
full of you
ほどけないリボン結び
An untieable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie my pinky tight
ねぇ baby 最初で最後の
Hey baby, make me your first and last
とくべちゅにしてね
special kiss
はーい！
Hii!
みんな、にゃっはろー！
Everyone, nyahallo!
エリートみこアイドルのさくらみこでーす！
I'm the elite miko idol, Sakura Miko!
いぇーい！
Yay!
さくらみこ生誕祭2026 ファッションビートに来てくれてどうもありがとうございまーす！
Thank you all so much for coming to Sakura Miko Birthday Live 2026 Fashion Beat!
いぇーい！
Yay!
えー今年でなんと、みこち18.8歳になりました！
And this year, Mikochi has turned 18.8 years old!
たぶん18.8歳だよね？
I'm probably 18.8, right?
はい。
Yes.
あの、0.1でね、刻んでいく系のVTuberですから、
Well, I'm the type of VTuber who ages in 0.1 increments,
今年も18.8歳になっちゃっておりまーす！わー！
so this year too, I've become 18.8 years old! Wah!
えー、そしてそして、今回のライブのテーマは
And, and, the theme for this concert is
ファッションビートにちなんでですね、
inspired by "Fashion Beat,"
ファッションとなっております！
it's all about "fashion"!
いろんなね、演出が盛りだくさんなので、ぜひ楽しんでください！
There are many different performances, so please enjoy them!
じゃあね、ちょっとまあファッションちなんで、
So, since it's fashion-themed,
みこちもちょっとだけチェンジしちゃおうかなー？
maybe Mikochi should do a little change too?
はい、上向いててください。
Okay, please look up.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
はい、じゃーん！
Okay, ta-da!
ということで、えー、クリスマスのね、ライブではね、
So, in the Christmas live,
あまり、あー...
not much, ah...
をしなかった
...didn't do.
こちらの、えー、キャストオフバージョンに
This is the, uh, 'cast-off' version...
なっておりまーす！
...that I'm wearing now!
こんな感じになってます、可愛いでしょ？
It looks like this, cute, right?
ちょっとセクシーですけどね
It's a little sexy, though.
はい！
Yes!
可愛いー！
So cute!
はい、次の曲はこれで披露しようと思っておりまーす！
Yes, I'm planning to perform the next song in this!
そして、えー、先ほどね、2曲ね
And, uh, just now, those two songs...
お送りしましたが、どうでしたか？
...that I performed, how were they?
みこのオリ曲の「ダイダイダイファンタジスタ」と
Miko's original song 'DAI DAI DAI FANTASISTA'...
そしてみこのね、あの、大好きなアイドルさんの、後藤真希さんの
...and then, a song by my favorite idol, Maki Goto...
「手を握って歩きたい」を披露させていただきました！
...'Te wo Nigitte Arukitai'!
とっても可愛かったでしょう？
It was really cute, wasn't it?
きゅんきゅん！
Kyun kyun!
はい！
Yes!
あ、そうだ、ステージもね、ちょっと見せたいんですけど
Oh, right, I also want to show you the stage.
見てください！
Please take a look!
こちら、今回のテーマにちなんで、作っていただきました！
This was made based on this time's theme!
ドレッサーとかね、めちゃくちゃね
The dresser and everything is just...
なんかこう、みこが小人になったみたいな感じですけど
It feels like Miko has become a tiny person.
ね、とっても可愛くなっております！
Right? It's turned out so cute!
そして、こちらのトルソーね
And then, these torsos...
みこちゃんの歴代の衣装とかも少し飾ってあります！
...are decorated with Miko's past costumes!
全部じゃないんですけどね
Not all of them, though.
はい！
Yes!
えー、そして
Uh, and then...
最後にですね、たくさんの告知があったりとか
...at the end, there are lots of announcements...
新衣装のお披露目もございますので
...and a new costume reveal!
ぜひ楽しんでもらえたらなと思っておりまーす！
So I hope you all enjoy it!
では！
Now then!
早速ゲストパート、行こうと思いますよー！
Let's head straight into the guest segment!
よいしょー！
Yoisho!
それでは、このあとも楽しんでね！
Well then, please enjoy what's coming next too!
よし！
Alright!
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
作詞・作曲：Yasutaka Nakata (capsule)
[Lyrics & Music: Yasutaka Nakata (capsule)]
おもしろいって いいたいのに
I want to say it's interesting
いえないなんて つまらないでしょ
But it's boring not being able to say it
おなじになって いい子でなんて
It's okay to be the same
いたくないって キミもそうでしょ
You don't feel pain, right?
だれかの
I don't want...
ルールに
...to be bound...
しばられたくはないの
...by someone's rules
わがまま
Selfish...
ドキドキ
...excitement
このままでいたい
I want to stay like this
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
このせまい
From this narrow...
こころの
...cage...
檻も
...of a heart
こわして
I want to break free...
自由になりたいの
...I want to be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
感覚をとぎすませてキミのように
Sharpen your senses like you
すいこまれてく螺旋模様みたいに
Like a spiral pattern, being sucked in,
I wanna be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
ただふつうに 生きたいのに
I just want to live normally
へんなことって つまらないでしょ
But weird things are boring, right?
きめつけないで いい子でなんて
Why decide what's good without trying?
いたくないって キミもそうでしょ
You don't feel pain, right?
だれかの
I don't want...
ルールの
...to be bound...
ルールに しばられたくはないの
I don't want to be bound by rules
わがまま ドキドキ
Selfish excitement
このままでいたい
I want to stay like this
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
鉄の首飾りをはずして
Take off the iron necklace
ただ自由にいきたいだけ
I just want to live freely
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
このせまいこころの檻も
This narrow cage of a heart
こわして自由になりたいの
I want to break it and be free
ファッションモンスター
Fashion Monster
新衣装公開
[Visual: New Outfit Reveal]
百鬼あやめ 登場
[Visual: Nakiri Ayame enters]
咲き誇れ 花よ 舞い踊れ
Let the flowers bloom, let them dance
明日を虹色に染め上げて
Coloring tomorrow in rainbow colors
夢色フェスティバル
[Title: Yumeiro Festival]
ソイヤ！ ソイヤ！
Soiya! Soiya!
はーどっこい！
Ha-dokkoi!
はっ！
Ha!
はっじまるぞー！
Here we go!
どっこいしょーどっこいしょ！
Dokkoisho, dokkoisho!
今から歌うは ウルトラスーパー
I'll sing it now, the ultra super
いといとおかしの 夢色リズムさ
Very, very charming Dream Color Rhythm
「おかし」な故にね 心惹かれるの
Because it's "charming," I'm drawn to it
まぁそんな噺は どうでもいいのさ
Well, that story doesn't really matter
大事なるのは 楽しむこころ
What's important is a heart that enjoys it
準備はいいかな? 遅れないでよね
Are you ready? Don't be late
あ! ちょい待ち!
Ah! Wait a sec!
囃子輝く街に 靴紐結んで
In the town with festive music, tie your laces
321で飛び出せ!
Jump out at 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの! ドキドキしたくない!?
I want to be excited! Don't you want to be nervous!?
ウキウキさせてよ! もういい?
Make me feel lighthearted! Is that enough?
いやいやまだまだ なんていうか止まらない?
No, no, not yet, I can't stop?
なんていうか止まれない!
I mean, I can't stop!
まだまだ明日の景色を見ていたくない?
Don't you want to keep seeing tomorrow's scenery?
咲き誇れ! 君もヨイサ!ヨイサ!
Bloom proudly! You too, Yoisa! Yoisa!
だから ここは最高のフェスティバル
That's why this is the best festival
祭囃子リズムで ノリノリさ
In high spirits with the festival music rhythm
笑顔満開➡︎無限大 It's Alright!
Full bloom smiles to infinity, it's alright!
舞い踊れ! ひぃふぅみぃで 染め上げ
Dance! Coloring it in with one, two, three
君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Tell me your color, the color I'm curious about
そんな感じで 良いさ!良いさ!
That's it, that's good! That's good!
夢のビート聴かせてよ
Let me hear the dream beat
続けて歌うは ウルトラスーパー
Next to sing is the ultra super
いといとおかしの 夢色リズムさ
Very, very charming Dream Color Rhythm
もしかしましても さっきも言ったっけ?
By any chance, did I say that already?
まぁそんな噺は どうでもいいのさ
Well, that story doesn't really matter
大事なるのは 信じるこころ
What's important is a believing heart
君だけ聞こえる リズムに任せて
Leave it to the rhythm only you can hear
あ!ちょい待ち!
Ah! Wait a sec!
星空きらめく街を
The town where the starry sky sparkles
もっともっと照らすくらい
Enough to light it up more and more
321で飛び出せ!
Jump out at 3, 2, 1!
ワクワクしたいの! ドキドキしたくない!?
I want to be excited! Don't you want to be nervous!?
ウキウキさせてよ! もういい?
Make me feel lighthearted! Is that enough?
いやいやまだまだ なんていうか終わらない?
No, no, not yet, it won't end?
なんていうか終われない!
I mean, it can't end!
今宵も夢色を抱きしめて
Embracing the dream colors tonight too
いっくぞー！
Let's go!
咲き誇れ!君もソイヤ!ソイヤ!
Bloom proudly! You too, Soiya! Soiya!
だから ここは最高のフェスティバル
That's why this is the best festival
曖昧なリズムに ドキドキさ
My heart pounds to the vague rhythm
空に満開➡︎無限大 It's Alright!
Full bloom in the sky to infinity, it's alright!
舞い上がれ!ひぃふぅみぃで染め上げ
Soar! Coloring it in with one, two, three
君色教えて 内緒にする color
Tell me your color, the secret color
そんな感じで 良いさ!良いさ!
That's it, that's good! That's good!
そんな感じで 良いさ！良いさ！
Just like that, it's good! It's good!
夢のビートきざもうよ
Let's carve out the beat of our dreams!
さわげー！
Make some noise!
咲き誇れ！君もヨイサ！ヨイサ！
Bloom in full glory! You too, Yoisa! Yoisa!
だから ここは最高のフェスティバル
That's why this is the best festival!
祭囃子リズムで ノリノリさ
Getting into the groove with the festival music!
笑顔満開➡︎無限大 It’s Alright!
Smiles in full bloom to infinity, It’s Alright!
舞い踊れ！ ひぃふぅみぃで 染め上げて
Dance! Dye it all in, one-two-three!
君色教えて 気になっちゃう color
Show me your color, I'm curious about your color.
そんな感じで 良いさ！良いさ！
Just like that, it's good! It's good!
夢のビート聴かせてよ
Let me hear the beat of your dreams!
だから止まれない！
So we can't stop!
はっ！
Ha!
ソイヤ！
Soiya!
どっこいしょーどっこいしょ
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
はーどっこい！
Ha, dokkoi!
恥ずかしいか青春は / 作詞・作曲：長屋晴子
[Song: Hazukashiika Seishunwa / Music & Lyrics: Haruko Nagaya]
ぶつけたところから熟れていく果実のように
Like a fruit that ripens from where it was bruised,
僕らは些細なことでへこたれたよな
we used to get discouraged over trivial things, didn't we?
かさぶたになれずに息せき切ってがむしゃらに
Without becoming a scab, gasping for breath and recklessly,
輝く一等星をめがけて手を伸ばしたよな
we reached out for the shining first-magnitude star, didn't we?
繊細されど大胆だ
Delicate, yet bold.
うるさい これが切り札だ
Shut up, this is our trump card!
泣き虫されど熱血だ
Crybaby, yet hot-blooded.
うるさい これが持ち味だ
Shut up, this is our style!
未開拓冒険地帯∴好奇心旺盛時代
Uncharted adventure zone ∴ Era of intense curiosity.
何が綺麗かは分かる 見る目ならばある
I know what's beautiful. I've got a good eye for it.
恥ずかしいか青春は
Are you embarrassed of your youth?
馬鹿らしいか真剣は
Is being serious ridiculous to you?
僕ら全力でやってんだ
We're giving it our absolute all!
振りかざせ存在を
Flaunt your existence,
掻き乱せ心臓を
and stir up your heart!
あとどれくらい続いていくだろう
I wonder how much longer this will continue.
守り抜いた青春が何よりもの贅沢だ
The youth we've protected is the greatest luxury of all.
きっといつか焦がれ思い返す
Surely, one day, we'll look back with longing.
名前のない関係を 捨てきれない感情を
Relationships without names, emotions we can't throw away...
何気ない今日を忘れないでね
Don't forget this ordinary day.
悩んでた種の色が昨日とはまるで違うとか
The color of the seeds you worried about is completely different from yesterday.
そんなの日常茶飯事だね
Things like that happen every day, don't they?
心は素直のようだ
The heart seems to be honest.
戦友だとか親友は
Whether we're comrades or best friends,
うるさい どれも正解だ
shut up, any of those are correct.
初恋だとか失恋は
Whether it's first love or heartbreak,
うるさい どれも宝石だ
shut up, they're all gems.
天才的 人生計画
A genius life plan
問題集 対抗美学
A workbook of rival aesthetics
君は 何してんのかな
I wonder what you're doing right now
話がしたい
I want to talk to you
風に乗って 青春が
Riding on the wind, our youth
この想いを 運んだ
Carried these feelings along
僕ら 全力を越えたいんだ
We want to go beyond our limits
立ちすくむ どうしたって
Even if we're standing still
引き連れて いこうぜ
Let's take everyone along
この上ない 今日を 過ごしたいよ
I want to spend this peerless day with you
今しかできない 事がある
There are things we can only do now
今しかできない
Only possible right now
恋がある
There's a love we can only have now
今しかできない
Only possible right now
から僕らに
Because of that
託された時間が 惜しい
The time entrusted to us is precious
今しか見られない
Only visible right now
君の笑顔も 君の涙も
Your smile and your tears
君の全ても
Even everything about you
大人びていく
It's all becoming more mature
有限だから 最高だ
It's the best because it's limited
恥ずかしいか 青春は
Is youth embarrassing to you?
馬鹿らしいか 真剣は
Is being serious ridiculous to you?
僕ら 全力でやってんだ
We're giving it our absolute all!
振りかざせ 存在を
Brandish your existence
掻き乱せ 心臓を
Stir up your heart
胸に刻めば
If you carve it into your chest
続いていくだだろう
It will surely continue
守り抜いた 青春が
The youth we've protected
何よりもの 贅沢だ
Is the greatest luxury of all
きっと いつか
Surely, someday
焦がれ 思い返す
We'll yearn and look back on it
名前のない関係を
This relationship without a name
捨てきれない感情を
These feelings we can't throw away
何気ない今日も 忘れないでね
Please don't forget this casual day
この上ない 今日を 忘れないでね
Please don't forget this peerless day
アイ！ アイドルだから
I-! Because I'm an idol
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging
君と夢見るんだ
Dreaming with you
不器用で悪いか
Is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I'll bloom in full glory!
咲き誇れアイドル
[Song: Bloom, My Idol]
初のイベント 需要無しデフォ
My first event, no demand was the default
そんな私が 夢を見ました
A person like that had a dream
アイドルという生き方
The way of life called 'idol'
憧れて
I yearned for it
「無敵エリート」 「笑顔はチート」
'Invincible Elite' 'My smile is a cheat'
こんな私を 見てくれる君
You, who watches me like this
好きなとこは どこですか？
What part of me do you like?
わがままを 許して
Please forgive my selfishness
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
Stage experience, with blurring tears
それでも 絶対負けたくない
Even so, I definitely don't want to lose
桜にメッセージ 乗せて届け
Delivering a message on the cherry blossoms
愛で溢れますように
May it overflow with love
アイドルだから 挑み続けるんだ
Because I'm an idol, I'll keep on challenging
君と夢見るんだ 不器用で悪いか
Dreaming with you, is it bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ 終わらせない
I won't let it end as just a delusion
私らしく 桜色 ね♡
Being myself, in cherry blossom pink, okay? ♡
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
My polished skills, showing my true ability
楽しめる日も 増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy have increased
アイドルとして 生きてる
I'm living as an idol
君のおかげ
All thanks to you
アホ毛はキュート！ 勝ち確ルート！
My cowlick is cute! It's a guaranteed win!
そんな私に ついてきてよね！
Follow along with me like this!
ドジなとこも 許されて 最強じゃん！
Even being clumsy is forgiven, isn't that the strongest?!
痛いの言いたいの グッと飲み込んで
I want to say 'it hurts', but I'll gulp it down
笑顔で 笑顔増やしたいな
I want to increase smiles with a smile
桜前線が 君の町に
Like the cherry blossom front to your town
春を届けるように
Delivering the spring
アイドルだけは 譲りたくないんだ
Only being an idol is something I won't give up
君に魅せたいんだ 理想へ挑むよ
I want to show you, challenging the ideal
駆け抜けろ
Run right through!
最高景色 見せてあげる
I'll show you the best scenery
信じていいよ 桜を
You can believe in the cherry blossoms
さぁ 皆で咲かそう
Now, let's all make it bloom
満開のピンクで 世界染めて
Dyeing the world in full-bloom pink
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears...
悲しい方じゃないから
aren't from sadness,
安心して
so don't worry.
きれいだね
It's beautiful...
今年も誕生日お祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday with me again this year!
みんな、大好きだよー！
Everyone, I love you!
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I'll keep on challenging myself.
君と夢見るんだ
I'll dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it wrong to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end with just a delusion.
私らしく
In my own way,
桜色 ね
cherry blossom pink, okay?
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうね
Thank you so much.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
お祝いしてくれてありがとうね
Thank you for celebrating with me.
楽しんでるー？
Are you having fun!?
見てるよ、みんな見てるよー！
I'm watching! I see you all!
ということで、ライブまだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますかー！？
So, are you ready to keep the live going!?
みんな！まだまだ見逃さないでね！
Everyone! Don't look away yet!
よいしょ、次の曲行きます！
Alright, on to the next song!
Fighting My Way
[Title: Fighting My Way]
Now I'm ready, I'm ready to go
花が咲く時が来たんだ
The time has come for the flower to bloom.
Are you ready? わかるでしょ
Are you ready? You know, right?
やってみせる Make it through
I'll show you I can make it through.
ほら そんな ソワソワしてたら
Look, if you're so restless like that...
時は過ぎちゃうから 今すぐにさ
...time will just pass by, so right now,
Let's work it out
もう 目を 背けやしないんだ
I won't turn my eyes away anymore.
自分で Make it better
I'll make it better myself.
作る正解を
Creating my own right answer.
I just wanna, just wanna find somebody
私よりも強気な ダレカ Uh
Someone more confident than me, uh.
夢中になる Make you hot
I'll be absorbed in it, make you hot.
準備体操お済みですか？
Are you done with your warm-ups?
掴むんだ Victory
I'll grab the victory!
So now let's start the war!
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay
A dream-like future, ay-ay,
信じて進むだけ
I'll just believe and move forward.
誰にも絶対
Against anyone, I absolutely...
負ける気なんかない
...have no intention of losing.
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond.
恋に踊れ
Dance in love,
情熱全て
all my passion.
もっと先を知りたい もう止まらない Ay-ay
I want to know what's further ahead, I won't stop anymore, ay-ay.
I will lead the way
Just come along my way
Hey!
Don't kill my vibe
行こう 一番上まで
Let's go to the very top!
ちょっと待ってよなんか
Wait a second, somehow...
誤解なら困っちゃうな
...it'd be a problem if there's a misunderstanding.
ねぇ 蹴落とすため 戦う訳ではないの
Hey, I'm not fighting just to kick others down.
Just wanna keep challenging myself
こんな Fantasy ハマったら
If you get hooked on this kind of fantasy...
もっともっと欲しくなっちゃうよ
...you'll end up wanting more and more.
もう 何も 恐れはしないんだ
I won't fear anything anymore.
君となら行ける気がするから
Because I feel like I can go if I'm with you.
Come join us
ほら 今 聞こえて来るから
Look, I can hear it now...
Yea, 私の名を呼ぶ方へ
...yea, towards the place where they call my name.
I'm fighting my way
夢の未来 Ay-ay
A dream-like future, ay-ay,
信じて進むだけ
I'll just believe and move forward.
誰にも絶対
Against anyone, I absolutely...
負ける気なんかない
...have no intention of losing.
君に見せたいの 彼方の景色を
I want to show you the scenery beyond.
雨を受け 夜を抜け
Enduring the rain, passing through the night,
青空の光 求めた
I sought the light of the blue sky.
Whoa
一つも無駄はないさ
Not a single thing was in vain.
力(パワー)に変えて 輝いてくから
I'll turn it into power and keep on shining.
KIRA KIRA 雫弾けた
Sparkling, the droplets burst.
Ah 神の思し召しだ
Ah, it's God's will.
連れてくよ Make you high
I'll take you there, make you high.
後悔はさせませんわ
I won't let you regret it.
超えるんだ Boundary
I'll cross the boundary!
So now let's start the war!
I'm fighting with myself
負けなんてない Ay-ay
There's no such thing as losing, ay-ay,
勝負受けて立つだけ
I'll just take on the challenge.
もう自分以外
Other than myself,
私に勝てない
no one can beat me.
君がいれば 何度も立ち上がるわ
If you're there, I'll stand up again and again.
愛を歌え
Sing of love,
想い全て
all my feelings.
逃げたくはない 待てない まだ終われない Ay-ay
I don't want to run away, I can't wait, it's not over yet, Ay-ay
I need you to stay
You make me feel okay
Hey!
It's time to shine
行こう 空の上まで
Let's go, to the top of the sky
Weh oh weh oh
Ram pam pam para pum pum pa
Ahhh ooh uh
唸るぜ 血泥ついたって 守りたい
I'm roaring, even if I'm covered in blood and mud, I want to protect
革命道中 だって 君に夢中
The revolution is on the way, I'm addicted to you after all
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found in a world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love
革命道中
[Title: Revolution on the Way]
甘くぬかるんだ眼差し
Sweet, muddy gaze,
変に色気あるから困った
it's troublesome because it's strangely sexy
手を繋ぐ勇気出したくて
I want to gather the courage to hold hands,
身の程わきまえてちゃ出来ないね
but I can't if I know my place
暗いトンネルの壁 したたり落ちる秘密
Secrets dripping down the walls of the dark tunnel
しめやかに高鳴る心
Quietly, my heart is pounding
ダメダメ... 待て待て...
No, no... wait, wait...
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace curses and illnesses too
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay to go wild around here?
あぁ唸るぜ 血泥ついたって 守りたい
Ah, I'm roaring, even if I'm covered in blood and mud, I want to protect
革命道中 だって 君に夢中
The revolution is on the way, I'm addicted to you after all
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found in a world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love
ダメダメ... 待て待て...
No, no... wait, wait...
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to be by your side without caring about appearances
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I'm even expecting it from a clumsy you
しがみつけば 消えそうな火に
If I cling to it, to the fire that seems to go out
恋の爪立てて近づいてもいい?
Can I get close by setting the claws of love?
身を任せ 抱かれて 全て失ってもいい
Give myself to it, be embraced, it's fine to lose everything
しめやかに高鳴る心
Quietly, my heart is pounding
ダメダメ... 待て待て...
No, no... wait, wait...
呪いも病も君となら
If I'm with you, even curses and illnesses
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay to go wild around here?
あぁ泣けるぜ 絶句しちゃうまで離れない
Ah, I'm roaring, I won't leave until I'm speechless
革命道中 だって 君に夢中
The revolution is on the way, I'm addicted to you after all
揺蕩う旅の狭間で見つけた
I found in the intervals of the swaying journey
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love
突き進むなら 二人で
If we're going to push forward, let's do it together
革命道中 だって 夢に熱中
The revolution is on the way, I'm addicted to dreams
ダメダメ... 待て待て...
No, no... wait, wait...
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace curses and illnesses too
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
Is it okay to go wild around here?
怖くたって 唸るぜ 血泥ついたって 守りたい
Even if it's scary, I'm roaring, even if I'm covered in blood and mud, I want to protect
革命道中 だって 君に夢中
The revolution is on the way, I'm addicted to you after all
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found in a world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
a sentimental love
CHaNGE
[Title: CHaNGE]
とべ、起こせ！ 願うは事故
Fly, wake it up! The wish is an accident
一世一代 さあ何賭す？ 自問自答
Once in a lifetime, come on, what will you bet? Self-questioning
勝つか負けるか ドローなんてないわ
Win or lose, there's no such thing as a draw
Ah Ah Ah yeah
幕開けるわ
I'll open the curtain
かっちんして
Roll the dice
ラッキーマネー
Lucky money
どっちもむり
Either way is impossible
Cigar, cigar
引けるかいなか
You gonna back down or no?
自分次第だな
It's up to you
余裕で！振り切り全BETだぜい
It's a piece of cake! I'll give it everything I've got and BET it all, yay
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
そこどけ！そう このエース
Out of the way! Yeah, this ace
かっさらうのはあたしだ
The one who'll snatch this ace is me
Stay もういい
Stay, I've had enough!
勝ったなら平常心
Winning brings peace of mind
ね playboy いけ
Hey, playboy, get out!
Don't get in my way
じゃあねだまって
See ya, and shut up
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down, sit down
はーもうフリーズ決めてや
Ah— Now I'm frozen for sure
投げるのは賽？才？かさじか
Is it the dice I'm throwing? My talent? Or my hands in the air?
そんな小さい尺 じゃ測れない
I can't measure with such a small ruler
でしょう そうでしょう say good bye や
Right? Don't you agree? Say goodbye
あっちこっちそっちどっち
Is it over there, here, or there?
Nothing, nothing やむ
I suffer from nothing, nothing
道なき道より
Darker and more unpleasant
やみやみいや
Than a trackless path
空回りしそうでもまだ止めないで
I feel like I'm just going in circles, but I can't stop yet
Ah 飲まれそう
The surrounding voices overwhelm me
声声、それぞれに
Each and every one
Get one’s way!
あんたはここまで
Alright, that's it for ya
後ろだけ見とけ
Just sit back and watch
かっちんして
Roll the dice
ラッキーマネー
Lucky money
どっちもむり
Either way is impossible
Cigar, cigar
引けるかいなか
You gonna back down or no?
自分次第だな
It's up to you
余裕で！振り切り全BETだぜい
It's a piece of cake! I'll give it everything I've got and BET it all, yay
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
そこどけ！そう このエース
Out of the way! Yeah, this ace
かっさらうのはあたしだ
The one who'll snatch this ace is me
Stay もういい
Stay, I've had enough!
勝ったなら平常心
Winning brings peace of mind
ね playboy いけ
Hey, playboy, get out!
Don't get in my way
じゃあねだまって
See ya, and shut up
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down, sit down
まさかの bye bye
An unexpected bye bye
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three
Sit down, sit down
特報！
Breaking News!
フルアニメーションMV
Full Animation Music Video
配信後プレミア公開！
Premiere after the stream!
MV公開に先駆けてー
Leading up to the MV release...
ARE YOU READY?
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
痛くて
Painful,
目を塞いでも
even if I close my eyes
聞こえちゃう
I can hear it,
不安ショ
anxiety and fear
悩んでも変わらないから
It won't change even if I worry
なんだかんだ
What can I do, what should I do
やるしかないか
I have no choice but to do it,
I have no choice
壊れるならいっそ
If I'm going to break, I might as well
直しやすいように
Make it easy to fix
どんな形
What kind of shape
目指せるかな
can I aim for?
助走なしの
Without a running start,
ジャンプ
jump
いまなしで
Without a plan,
ダイブ
dive
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
Today's me, I want to praise myself
息したい
I want to breathe,
もっと響きたい
I want to resonate more
ねえあたし以上が見れるかも
Hey, maybe I can see something beyond myself
妄想止まんないや
I can't stop the delusions
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
抱きでみちゃい
I want to hug and see
夢にありそうな
Something that seems to be in a dream
なんて
Just like that
はけやしないな
I can't just brush it off
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Fulfilling it is up to me
それとも誰かにおまかせ
Or leave it to someone else
たんだ
It's fine,
it's fine
自分に勝ちたい
I want to win against myself
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
愛を喰ら
Devour the love
負けるなんて
Losing?
ごめんた
I'm sorry, that
味がしないな
has no flavor
何度でも 灰になる進化
Every time, I evolve even if I become ash
生まれ変われる
I can be reborn
バカボケでシンケン
Don't be stupid, be serious
まだ
Still,
still
腐らせてあげない
I won't let you rot
そんなー
Like that...
チクチク刺してくるのは
Pricking at me over and over again,
飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm so sick and tired of it
ごめん
Sorry,
鬱陶しい
but please keep
言葉遊びは
this annoying wordplay
どうかちゃんと仕舞っておいて
to yourself
私こそがライバル
I am my own rival
当たり前の解釈
That's the obvious interpretation
どうしたらいい
I already know the answer to
わかってるのに
"What should I do?"
助走なしの
Without a running start,
ジャンプ
jump
いまなしで
Without a plan,
ダイブ
dive
今日のあたし 出来る気しないなって
Today, I don't feel like I can do it...
気にしないなんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible not to care?
ねえあたし以外と比べても
Hey, even if I compare myself to others,
クソつまんないじゃんか
it's just so damn boring
ファッションビート
Fashion Beat
抱きでみちゃい？
I want to hug and see?
夢にありそうな
Something that seems to be in a dream
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just spit out "whatever" at my dreams
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is it me who will make them come true?
それとも誰かにお任せか
Or should I leave it to someone else?
ただ ただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, I just want to win against myself
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らう
New Fashion Beat, eating up love
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I refuse to lose, it tastes like nothing
何度でも灰になる進化
Evolution that turns to ash, again and again
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a bug that is reborn
まだ まだ腐ってあげない
Still, I won't let myself rot yet
そう、ない
That's right, I won't
止まれない
I cannot stop
誰かじゃない あたし自身だ
It's not someone else, it's myself
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a bug that is reborn
まだ まだ散ってあげない
Still, I won't let myself wither yet
そう、ない
That's right, I won't
みんなライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thanks for watching the live!
これからは告知のお時間です
Now it's time for some announcements.
まずは、こちら！
First, this!
さくらみこ誕生日記念2026 記念グッズです！
Sakura Miko Birthday Memorial 2026 commemorative goods!
まずは、1つ目！ こちら、ドーン！
First, item number one! Here it is, boom!
アクリルパネル！
Acrylic panel!
イラストレーターは、おるだん先生に描き下ろしていただきました
The illustration was drawn specially by Ordan-sensei.
テーマは『電脳世界のミコ』！
The theme is "Miko of the Cyber World"!
新衣装のミコを描き下ろしてもらいました
I had her draw Miko in the new outfit.
オーロラ加工でキラキラのアクリルパネルとなっております
It's a sparkling acrylic panel with an aurora finish.
めっちゃ可愛い！
It's so cute!
続いては、こちら！
Next up is this!
スマホスタンドフィギュアです！
Smartphone stand figure!
スマホが立てかけられるスタンド、そして新衣装のミコのフィギュア
A stand for your phone, and a figure of Miko in her new outfit.
めちゃくちゃ可愛くないですか、これ？
Isn't this incredibly cute?
たくさんこだわったので、ぜひね
I put a lot of thought into it, so please,
このスタンドにスマホを立てかけて配信見てくれたら嬉しいです
I'd be happy if you prop up your phone and watch streams on it.
続いては、こちら！
Next up!
ガジェットケース！
Gadget case!
新衣装にちなんで、あまり出さないグッズも考えてみました
Inspired by the new outfit, I thought of some unique goods.
ケーブルやモバイルバッテリーなど小物を収納できるケースです
It's a case for storing cables, power banks, and other small items.
ソフトな素材になってるよ
It's made of a soft material.
最後は、こちら！
Finally, this!
ナイロンジャケット！
Nylon jacket!
新衣装をモチーフにしたナイロンジャケットとなっております
This nylon jacket is themed after the new outfit.
ちょっとかっこよめのデザインなので
It has a somewhat cool design,
みんな一緒にお揃いになってくれたら嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if we could all wear matching ones!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full set purchase bonus!
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードです！
It's a postcard with a handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
ちょっと数量限定にはなるんですが
It's available in limited quantities,
みんなお早めに、よろしくお願いします！
so everyone, please get yours early!
通常版は、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードです
The regular version comes with a foil-stamped signature and message.
みんな、ぜひね、たくさん手に入れてくれると嬉しいです！
Everyone, I'd be happy if you could get lots of them!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
そして、告知2つ目は、こちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと、学研さんの参考書シリーズが発売決定になりました！
My reference book series from Gakken will be released!
ホロライブStudyBook、さくらみこでもわかるシリーズです
The "Even Sakura Miko Can Understand" Hololive Study Book series.
中学漢字＋語彙、中学数学
Junior high Kanji + Vocabulary, and Junior high Math,
中学英単語、中学地理＋都道府県の4冊が発売決定です！
English Words, and Geography + Prefectures—all four will be released!
そして、初回限定の愛蔵版も発売予定となっております
And a first-press limited collector's edition is also planned.
4月下旬頃より予約開始なので、続報チェックしてね！
Reservations start in late April, so keep checking for news!
ミコでもわかるシリーズ、んー
The "Even Miko Can Understand" series... hmm.
みんな説得力があると思うよね！
I think everyone will find that very persuasive!
次！ 3つ目は、こちら！
Next! The third one is this!
さくらみこ×フレーベル館、初の絵本！
My very first picture book with Froebel-kan!
『みこぴーとおおきなさくらのき』が本日より発売です！
"Mikopee and the Big Cherry Tree" is on sale starting today!
もう買ってくれた人もいるかな？
Has anyone already bought it?
いつも支えてくれているみこぴーを題材に絵本を作りました
I made this book featuring the Mikopee who always support me.
全国の書店やローソンで購入可能なので、ぜひ手に取ってください！
It's at bookstores and Lawson nationwide, so please pick one up!
よろしくお願いします！ 頑張りました！
Thank you! I worked really hard on it!
続いてはこちら、大発表！
And now for a major announcement!
4つ目は、こちら！
The fourth announcement!
さくらみこフィギュア化が決定しました！
A Sakura Miko figure release has been decided!
ミコの夢だった等身大フィギュアがついに完成です！
The life-size figure that was my dream is finally complete!
やったー！
Yay!
スケールフィギュアも同時に予約販売が決まりました
Scale figures are also going up for reservation.
明日、3月6日から予約開始です
Reservations start tomorrow, March 6th.
エキスポのデザインココさんブースで展示されるので見てね！
It will be displayed at the Design COCO booth at the Expo!
たくさん写真撮ってね！
Please take lots of photos!
また、この等身大フィギュアも展示される
Also, where this life-size figure will be shown,
京都IP書店とのポップアップショップも開催決定です！
a pop-up shop with Kyoto IP Bookstore has been decided!
すごい！
Amazing!
リニューアルオープンした京都 蔦屋 IP書店にて開催です
It will be held at the newly reopened Kyoto Tsutaya IP Bookstore.
みなさーん！
Everyone!
4月28日から開催でーす！
It starts from April 28th!
さくらみこ POP UP SHOP 京都IP書店 オープン記念
[Title: Sakura Miko POP UP SHOP at Kyoto IP Shoten - Opening Commemoration]
オリジナルグッズの発売や、
Original goods will be on sale, and...
ノベルティのコラボも行われるので、
there will also be a novelty collab,
みなさん楽しみにしてくださーい！
so everyone, please look forward to it!
盛りだくさんだー！
It's packed with stuff!
そして、まだございまーす！
And there's more!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
さくらみこ×HYTE コラボPCケース 発売決定！
[Visual: Sakura Miko x HYTE Collab PC Case Release Confirmed!]
さくらみこ×HYTE、コラボPCケース、発売決定！
Sakura Miko x HYTE, collab PC case, release confirmed!
キーキャップとデスクマットのセットもございます。
There's also a set with keycaps and a desk mat.
先行予約リリースや、詳細については、
For pre-order release and details,
hyte.co/miko を見てみてください。
please check out hyte.co/miko.
楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to it!
そして、今年も！
And this year too!
鳴門鯛焼本舗×さくらみこ コラボ
[Visual: Naruto Taiyaki Hompo x Sakura Miko Collab]
さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗さんのコラボが実施中でーす！
The Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Hompo collab is underway!
今年でなんと、4回目です！ありがとうございます。
It's the 4th time this year! Thank you very much.
3月31日までなので、みんなぜひ食べに行ってください！
It's until March 31st, so everyone, please go and eat some!
続いて、
Next,
新曲 FASHIONBEAT 本日24時よりリリース！
[Visual: New Song 'FASHIONBEAT' Released Today at 24:00]
新曲、FASHIONBEAT、本日0時よりリリースでーす！
the new song, FASHIONBEAT, is released from 0:00 today!
MVはこの後プレミア公開！みんな見てね！
The MV premiere is after this! Everyone, watch it!
とっても豪華なアニメMVとなっております。よろしくお願いします。
It's a very luxurious anime MV. Please check it out.
はい、そして、こちら！
Yes, and this!
hololive SUPER EXPO 2026 & hololive 7th fes.
[Visual: hololive SUPER EXPO 2026 & hololive 7th fes.]
明日から、ホロライブエキスポとセブンスフェス開催でーす！
From tomorrow, Hololive Expo and 7th Fes are being held!
3日間の開催ですよー！すごーい！
It's a 3-day event! Amazing!
みこはですね、セブンスフェスではDay 2のステージ2に参加します。
As for Miko, I'll be participating in Stage 2 of Day 2 for the 7th Fes.
みんな見に来てね！
Everyone, come and see me!
その後は、メンバー限定の撮影会もあるので、
After that, there's also a member-only photo session,
みんなみこぴーになってね！
so everyone, become a Mikopi!
ということで、告知がもりもりもりだくさんになりましたが、
So, the announcements became super, super packed,
みんなついてこれたかな？
but did everyone manage to keep up?
みこ、これからも頑張るので、よろしくお願いします。
Miko will keep doing her best from now on, so please support me.
誕生日祝ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for celebrating my birthday!
おつみこー！
Otsumiko!
出演：さくらみこ、戌神ころね、百鬼あやめ...
[Credits: Cast - Sakura Miko, Inugami Korone, Nakiri Ayame...]
痛くて 目を塞いでも
Even if it hurts and I close my eyes,
聞こえちゃう 不安ショー
I can still hear it, the anxiety show.
悩んでも変わらないから
Since worrying won't change anything,
なんだかんだやるしかないか
I guess I have to just do it, after all.
壊れるならいっそ直しやすいように
If I'm going to break, I'd rather break in a way that's easy to fix.
どんな形目指せるかな
What kind of shape can I aim for?
助走なしのジャンプ
A jump without a run-up,
紐無しでダイブ
A dive without a safety line,
今日のあたし 褒めてあげたいじゃんか
I really want to praise myself for today, don't I?
息したい もっと響きたい
I want to breathe, I want to resonate more,
ねえあたし以上が見れるかも
Hey, maybe I can see something beyond myself.
妄想止まんないや
My imagination won't stop.
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Want to try sniffing out a fashion beat?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just say 'whatever' to my dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is it me myself who will fulfill them?
それとも誰かにお任せか
Or should I leave it to someone else?
ただ ただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, just want to win against myself.
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らう
New fashion beat, devouring love,
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I won't accept losing, it has no taste.
何度でも灰になる進化
Evolution that turns to ash, again and again,
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a reborn bug.
まだ まだ腐ってあげない
I'm not, I'm not going to rot away yet,
そう、ない
No, not at all.
チクチク刺してくるのは
What keeps pricking at me,
飽き飽きしてるわ
I'm already sick of it.
ごめん 鬱雑い 言葉遊びは
Sorry, all those annoying word games,
どうか ちゃんと 仕舞っておいて
Please, just put them away properly.
私こそがライバル 当たり前の解釈
I am my own rival, that's an obvious interpretation,
どうしたらいい わかってるのに
Even though I know what I should do.
助走なしのジャンプ
A jump without a run-up,
紐なしでダイブ
A dive without a safety line,
今日のあたし できる気しないなって
'I don't feel like I can do it today,'
気にしない なんて無理じゃない？
Isn't it impossible to say I don't care?
ねえあたし以外と比べても
Hey, even if I compare myself to others,
クソつまんないじゃんか
Isn't it just boring as hell?
ファッションビート 嗅いでみちゃう？
Want to try sniffing out a fashion beat?
夢にあっそなんて吐けやしないな
I can't just say 'whatever' to my dreams.
叶えるのはあたし自身か
Is it me myself who will fulfill them?
それとも誰かにお任せか
Or should I leave it to someone else?
ただ ただ自分に勝ちたい
I just, just want to win against myself.
ニューファッションビート 愛を喰らう
New fashion beat, devouring love,
負けるなんてごめんだ 味がしないな
I won't accept losing, it has no taste.
何度でも灰になる進化
Evolution that turns to ash, again and again,
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a reborn bug.
まだ まだ腐ってあげない
I'm not, I'm not going to rot away yet,
そう、ない
No, not at all.
止まれない
I can't stop,
誰かじゃない あたし自身だ
It's not anyone else, it's me myself.
生まれ変わるバグの擬人化
Personification of a reborn bug,
まだ まだ散ってあげない
I'm not, I'm not going to scatter yet,
そう、ない
No, not at all.
生誕LIVE 2026 今年も祝ってくれてありがとう
[Visual: Birthday LIVE 2026 - Thank you for celebrating with me again this year!]
みんなのおかげでたくさんのことを乗り越えてみこでいられてるよ。
[Visual: Thanks to everyone, I've overcome many things and am able to be Miko.]
まだまだ笑っていよう!!
[Visual: Let's keep smiling!!]
そしてこれからもキミとあきらめない心でアイドルがんばる!!
[Visual: And from now on, I'll do my best as an idol with you and an unyielding heart!!]
さくらみこ 2026.3.5
[Visual: - Sakura Miko, 2026.3.5]
生誕LIVE 2026 ♡ 今年も祝ってくれてありがとうにぇー♡
みんなのおかげでたくさんのことを乗りこえてこられたよ。 まだまだ笑っていこう!!
[Birthday LIVE 2026] Thank you for celebrating with me again this year-nye! ♡
Thanks to everyone, I've been able to overcome so much. Let's keep on smiling!!
これからもキラみ続ける あきらめない心でアイドルがんばる!!
さくらみこ 2026.3.5
I'll keep on sparkling and do my best as an idol with a never-give-up spirit!!
— Sakura Miko 2026.3.5